说你明白了
Say you understand.
你明白了么
Do you understand?
告诉我你明白了  索尔
Tell me you understand, Saul!
每一块钱
Every dollar--
如果二十四小时内没有我的消息
if you don't hear from me in 24 hours--
不  不  索尔  索尔  闭嘴
No, no. Saul. Saul, shut up.
闭嘴听我说
Shut up and listen to me.
我要你把钱全都给她
I want you to give her every last dollar.
我不管需要不需要把钱装进箱子里
I don't care if you have to stuff it in trash bags.
就全给她就行了
Just make sure she gets everything.
好么  务必做到
All right? Just make it happen!
您好  这里是怀特家
Hi. You've reached the White family.
有事留言
Please leave a message.
是我
hey. It's me.
我   我
I-- I...
我就是想说
I just wanted to say
我一直挂念着你
that I was thinking about you
挂念着孩子
and the kids, and, uh...
我爱你
I love you.
第四季 第五集
S04E05: Shotgun
您好  您想尝尝
Hello. Would you like to try
我们的鸡肉饼早餐套餐么
our Breakfast Chicken Chalupa Combo Meal?
古斯・福林
Gus Fring.
您说什么
Excuse me?
古斯塔沃・福林  你的老板  叫他出来
Gustavo Fring, your boss, now.
谢谢
Please.
福林先生不在
Mr. Fring isn't here right now.
有什么我能帮忙的么  -他就在这
- Is there something I'm able-  - He's here.
他的车就停在外面  他就在这
His car's parked out front. He's here.
他刚才在这  福林先生
He was here. Mr. Fring was--
你去后面
You just go in the back
告诉他我是沃尔特・怀特
and you tell him it's Walter White.
明白了么
Understand?
他知道是什么事
He'll know what it's about.
我在这等着
I'll wait.
你好
Hello.
沃尔特  你在干什么
Walter, what exactly are you doing?
杰西在哪
Where's Jesse?
杰西跟我在一起  他没事
Jesse's with me. He's fine.
你觉得我信么
Do you expect me to just believe that?
我向你发誓  沃尔特
I'm crossing my heart, Walter.
他在哪
Where is he?
等下
Hold on.
喂
Yo.
杰西
Jesse?
是我  有事么
Yeah. What's up?
杰西  你在哪
Jesse, w-where are you?
和麦克在一起
With Mike.
我知道你和麦克在一起
I know you're with Mike.
你没事吧
Are-- Are you all right?
他是不是拿枪指着你呢
Does he have a gun on you?
没有
No.
那你们干什么呢
Well, what's going on, then?
开车
We're driving.
Driving?
去哪
Driving where?
不清楚
I don't know.
向北吧
Uh, north.
他为什么开车带着你
W-W-- Why is he driving you?
他要去哪
Where is he going?
不知道
Beats me.
我...我
I-- I don't-- I--
让麦克接电话
Put Mike back on.
你好
Hello again.
麦克  告诉我你们打算干什么
Mike, tell me know exactly what is going on.
杰西今天跟着我  你就老老实实
Jesse's with me today, so what you need to do
回实验室继续制毒
is to go back to your lab and get on with the cook.
你得自己把活干完
You're gonna have to muddle through this one without him, okay?
就是这么个情况
That's what's going on.
但是这
But it doesn't--
再见  沃尔特
Goodbye, Walter.
麦克
Mike--
先生
Sir--
打扰一下  先生
Excuse me. Hey.
你不能到后面来
You're not allowed back there.
抱歉  先生
Excuse me, sir.
我告诉您了  福林先生不在这
As I said, sir, Mr. Fring is not here.
这里是顾客禁区
This area's for employees only,
您得马上离开
and I have to ask that you leave immediately.
你告诉怀特老师的话
What you told Mr. White, that's...
都是扯淡  是吧
that's just bullshit, right?
你就打算把我扔到什么荒郊野岭去是吧
You, uh, you figure on just leaving me in some ditch?
你很关心么
What do you care?
不
I don't.
但我得和你说明白了  你最好打准点
But I'll tell you now, you better shoot straight,
老头
old man,
不然我就把先把你的另一只耳朵
or I'll slice off your other ear
割下来
before this is over.
你走么
You coming?
这活今天我们还得再做六遍
We got to do this six more times today,
每次中间还有很长的路要开
with a lot of miles in between.
我希望天黑之前能完成
I'd like to finish before dark.
这个怪胎  我给你说
This freaking guy, I tell you what.
就好像是疤面煞星和罗杰斯先生
It's like Scarface had sex
做爱一样
with Mister Rogers or something.
谁说做这个啊
Who does this, you know?
你追查的毒贩  海森伯格
Your boy Heisenberg.
还以为我们已经抓住他了
Thought we had him already.
是啊  你就想吧
Yeah. Keep dreaming.
是啊  不是
Yeah, no.
盖茨几个月前抓住过他
Getz busted him a few months back.
是么  不是瞧不起
Yeah, well, no offense
这个杜奇・豪瑟探员
to Detective Doogie Howser there,
Doogie Howser  天才小医生主角名字
他抓住的只是个笨蛋重刑犯
but all he caught was a dipshit lifer
名字叫惯犯吉米
by the name of Jimmy In-N-Out.
这个  这是你要找的海森伯格么
This one-- he's your Heisenberg?
是的  我觉得他是
Yeah, I believe he is.
那你是怎么判断的
So what are you thinking?
竞争对手的毒品团伙所为
Rival drug gang taking out the mastermind?
有什么嫌疑人物需要我查么
Any names I should check out?
希望我能帮上你
I wish I could help you there.
我只认识两个和蓝色冰毒有关的人
Only two people I know connected with the blue stuff.
一个整天带着小童帽的废柴
Uh, one is a beanie-wearing j-- stain
叫布兰登・梅休
by the name of Brandon Mayhew--
道上的名字  猴子
street name, uh, Badger.
绝对是个小角色
Definitely another player.
另一个  杰西・平克曼
The other one is, uh, Jesse Pinkman.
他和我还有段故事
He and I have a history.
是啊
Yeah.
你觉得平克曼是杀手么
You see Pinkman as a shooter?
那我会很吃惊的
That would surprise me.
我们合成了一个嫌疑人的画像
Well, we got a composite of a person of interest.
是邻居在伯蒂切家
It's a guy the neighbors saw
发生枪击之后看到的
at Boetticher's place right after the shooting.
没印象
Eh...sorry.
不  留着吧  以防万一
No, hang on to it, just in case.
我们还弄到几个指纹来检验身份
Then we got a couple of prints we're hoping to I.D.
如果有匹配的
If I get any kind of hit,
我会通知你
I'll keep you in the loop on that.
你知道  提姆
You know, uh, Tim,
听着  我很感谢你做的事情  真的
look, I appreciate what you're doing, really--
就是一直让我参与此事
uh, you know, keeping me involved and all,
但是  你知道
but, uh, you know,
看到海森伯格就这样死了
finding this guy Heisenberg dead like this...
我要说
I have to say, it, uh...
对我来说就算谢幕了
kind of feels like closure to me, you know?
汉克  你能帮我们很大的忙
Hank, you really are a big help here.
我知道  我了解
No, I know. I get it, really.
但是  我已经完成使命了
But I'm done.
别这样
Oh, no.
你不用这样
You don't need to do that.
这不是我在这的原因么
This is why I'm out here, right?
给你打后援
To be, like, your backup?
那么说如果我在这给你当保镖
So if I'm out here in a guard-type capacity
看着这些钱
to watch over the money,
那我得需要一支枪对吧
that means I need, like, a gun, right?
不对
Nope.
要是没枪
I mean, isn't that, like, completely idiotic
我站在这不成傻子了么
for me to be out here without a gun?
我来这干什么
I mean, you haven't said dick
你也不告诉我
about what I'm supposed to be doing here,
然后还不给我枪
and I'm supposed to do it without a gun?
这根本没道理啊
How does that even make sense?
怎么了
What?
我能抽烟的  对吧
I can smoke, right?
不可能
Not a chance.
谬论啊
Fallacies
一个给你  两个给我
One for you and two for me
我终于知道计划是什么了
It's finally hitting me what the-- the plan is here.
就是想把我无聊死  那么
It's to bore me to death, so...
太管用了  任务成功了
mission accomplished because it's totally working.
做的好
Great job.
你知道么  我完全明白
You know, I really do get what's going on
这些接头点和现金的作用
with all the dead drops and bags of cash.
当年我贩毒的时候
I mean, my boys had the exact same system
我的手下也是这么搞的
when I was running things.
我的员工
My crew.
利润虽然没你们的丰厚
Nowhere near the same cheese you guys are slinging,
但道理是一样的
but same theory--
把供货商和经销商完全分离
to maintain separation between dealer and supplier,
规避风险
reduce risk,
等等
et cetera.
不是  你不觉得你来我往的对话
Look, don't you think it would be good
会更好些么
if there was some back and forth communication here?
你让我坐在副驾驶上
You got me riding shotgun
让我见识了这个州最黑暗的角落
to every dark anal recess of this state.
对我友善点  给我透点消息
Be nice if you clued me in a little.
我来这是干活的
I mean, I'm here to do a job, right?
我是说  如果我就是这个人
And, I mean, yo, like, if I'm the guy,
你至少得告诉我这到底是怎么一回事吧
then you should just tell me what the hell's up.
怎么了
What?
你不是那个人
You are not the guy.
你当不了那个人
You're not capable of being the guy.
我本来有个人  但现在我没有了
I had a guy, but now I don't.
你  不是那个人
You are not the guy.
那告诉我  我到底是来干什么的
Then what the hell am I doing here?
我不知道  我说了不算
I don't know. It's not my call.
我只是奉命行事
I just do what I'm told,
现在你也要奉命从事
and now you're gonna do what you're told,
那就是  坐好  闭嘴
which is to sit here, shut up,
呆在车里  直到把活干完
and stay in the car till we finish our pickups.
明白了么
You got it?
要改变主意么
We having second thoughts?
时刻都有
Every hour of every day.
给你们说  这是绝对正常的
Let me tell you, that is perfectly normal.
但你们的预期是实际的
But your expectations are realistic.
你们有一个妥善  可靠的商业计划
You have a good, solid business plan.
我感觉很有信心
I'm feeling very confident.
你们有很大的机会来做成这件事
You have an excellent shot at making this work.
沃尔特
Walt.
没问题吧
We good?
没有
Yeah.
好的
All right.
祝贺您二位
Well, my congratulations to the both of you.
谢谢你  艾伦
Thank you very much, Alan.
不客气
It is my pleasure.
怀特先生
Mr. White.
祝您好运
Best of luck.
谢谢
Thank you.
下周我先把我的车开过来
I'm bringing my car over first thing next week
清洁打蜡
for a wash and wax.
期待你的到来
Oh, well, we'll be looking for you.
我会来的
I'll be there.
再次感谢
Thank you again.
不客气
You're welcome.
-再见  -再见
- Bye-bye. - Bye-bye.
这回成真了
Wow. It's official.
感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
我
I'm...
我  你感觉怎么样
well, I'm-- How do you feel?
紧张
Uh...nervous.
害怕
Scared.
这是巨大的一步  沃尔特
This is a big step, Walt.
如果我们做的对
If we don't do this right--
我们会很好的
We'll be fine.
会么
We will?
再给我说一遍
Tell me again.
我们会很好的  相信我
We will be fine. Believe it.
如果我们要这样
If we're going to do this--
如果我们真的要这样
I mean, we're really going to do this--
那我们得向对方保证
then we have to promise each other
不能再有秘密
no more secrets.
再也不能出现之前的错误了
There can't be any mistakes like before.
要绝对坦诚
There has to be complete honesty.
我完全赞成
I'm all for that.
好
Good.
那么
Well, then, uh,
喝一杯庆祝一下怎么样
how about a drink to celebrate?
现在  我们拥有一大间洗车房了
Well-- well, we own a big-a-- car wash now.
没错  我认为这值得庆祝
We do. I guess that merits a celebration.
别太贵的
Nothing too expensive.
明白  明白
Right. Right.
那就喝点普通的
Non-fancy liquor it is.
直到工作完成
Just as long as it gets the job done.
是我
Uh, it's me.
我就是想说
I just wanted to say
我一直挂念着你  挂念着孩子
that I was thinking about you and the kids,
还有
and, uh...
我爱你
I love you.
好了
Ok.
-快脱了  -好的
- Just take it off.  - Okay.
床单的味道和以前不一样了
The sheets, they smell different than I remember.
换了新的织物柔软剂
New fabric softener.
我很喜欢
Mm, I like it.
我
I, uh...
还换了个新发型
also got a new haircut.
不知道你
Don't know if you--
是的  我是想说点什么来着
Oh, yes, I-- I was going to say something.
真的么
Were you, really?
我确实很喜欢
I do like it.
谢谢
Thanks.
那明晚一起吃晚餐
So, um, dinner tomorrow night?
我跟玛丽说了我们会过去和他们一起吃
I told Marie that we'd come over and eat with them.
有空么
Uh, think maybe you'll be free?
有
Yeah.
我们一起去
Yeah, we can do that.
那样挺好的
That'll-- That'll be nice.
好
Good.
玛丽说这是能让汉克离开房间
Marie says it's about the only thing
唯一的办法
that'll get Hank out of his room.
妈妈
Mom.
妈妈  爸爸
Hey, Mom, Dad.
儿子
Hi, son.
你们在哪
Where are you?
我们在里屋
Uh, we're-- we're back here.
我们这就出来
We'll be out in a minute.
他知道你回来了
He knows that you're here.
我车停在外面呢
I'm parked in the driveway.
这下晚餐时间
Oh. This is going to make
可要添些有趣的话题了
for some very interesting dinner conversation.
他肯定要问到我们目前的生活状况
He's definitely going to ask about our living situation now.
也许
Maybe, uh...
也许你该搬回来住
maybe you should move back in,
这样
you know,
更容易向大家解释
just so it's, uh, easier to explain to everyone.
你觉得呢
You think?
我得回去工作了
I have to get back to work.
有时间安排的
You know, schedule.
明白
Yeah.
该死
Damn it.
喂
Hey!
这是两个人干的活
Hey! This is a two-man job!
我一个人做不来
I can't do it alone!
我受够了  够了  不干了
I'm done! That's it! Finished!
在我搭档回来之前  我罢工
Nothing else happens until I get my partner back.
杰西
Jesse?
杰西在哪
Where's Jesse?
我需要他
I need him.
你们这些人想让我
You people have me down here
一个人完成两个人的操作
trying to complete a two-man operation by myself!
这不可能
It's unacceptable.
这样很危险  后果不堪设想
It's dangerous and counterproductive.
杰西负责操作铲车  不是我
Jesse operates the forklift, not me.
这只是他在实验室
That's just one of the many,
做的很多事情之一
many things he does around the lab
这样才能让我们跟上进度
that keeps us on schedule,
所以我建议你们把他带回来
so I suggest that you get him back down here
在你们...
as soon as you p--
你在听我说话吗
Are you listening to me?
喂
Hello!
你想把它放哪
Where do you want it?
就是这儿了  对吧  最后一站
This is it, right? Last stop?
最后一站
Last stop?
我一直在数着
Hey, I've been counting, yo.
之后就完工了
No more pickups after--
谬论啊
Fallacies...
fallacies.
谬论啊  谬论啊
Fallacies, fallacies.
你一个  我一个
One for you, two for me.
谬论啊  谬论啊
Fallacies, fallacies...
我需要人来接我
Yeah. I'm gonna need to be picked up.
现在
Now.
市中心的加西亚咖啡
Garcia's on Central.
按一声喇叭  在停车场等我
Honk once. I'll meet you in the parking lot.
不必了
Cancel that.
有个家伙
Hey, this dude--
有个人朝我走来
this dude was coming right at me
手里拿着把猎枪
with a-- with a shotgun.
他们堵住了巷口
All right? They, like, blocked the alley,
打算对我们打劫
and they were going to rip us off, man.
我别无选择
I didn't have a choice, okay?
我不得不向后倒  撞上那家伙的车
I had to put it in reverse, slam into the guy's car,
就那么...
and just-- --
我看见了
I saw.
老天啊
Ah, Jesus.
我只是
I just--
我不知道
I don't know.
没关系  孩子
Go ahead, kid.
抽吧
Smoke up.
早上好
Good morning.
早上好  儿子
Hey. Good morning, son.
我给你倒点果汁吧
You want me to pour you some juice?
我要喝咖啡
I'll take coffee.
我都不知道你开始喝咖啡了
Didn't know you started drinking coffee.
是啊  我还开始系鞋带了
Yeah. I also started tying my own shoelaces, too,
全靠自己
all by myself.
去拿个杯子
Go grab a mug.
加奶还是糖
Milk? Sugar?
黑咖啡就好
Just black.
黑咖  我喜欢
Black. I like it.
老爸  我
Uh, hey, Dad, I, uh...
我想说
I-- I just got to say, um...
我只是想说
I-- I just wanted to say
有你在家真好
that it's really cool to have you here.
谢谢你  儿子
Thank you, son.
回家的感觉很好
It's cool to be back home.
感觉像是...
It just feels--
妈妈说你这周二会搬回来
Mom said you're moving back in, uh, this Tuesday.
她这么说的
She-- She said that?
是的
Yeah.
周二是吗
Tuesday, is it?
真是不错
How about that?
杰西
Jesse.
Jesse!
怎么了
Yo, what's up?
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
凿冰
Uh, breaking ice.
我是说  你在
I mean, what are you--
你怎么在这
what are you doing here?
你的车呢
Where's your car?
麦克载我来的
Mike dropped me off.
杰西
Jesse.
Jesse!
昨天发生了什么  你去哪儿了
What happened yesterday? Where were you?
我去陪麦克做交接
I was out with Mike helping him make pickups.
交接什么
Picking up what?
现金  还有货
Cash. Dead drops.
麦克去接货  我给他们放风
Mike made the pickups, and I guarded them.
你
You?
给麦克放风
Guarded Mike?
这是在开玩笑吗
What is this, some kind of a joke?
你知道吗  有两个人想打劫我们
Hey, you know what? Two dudes tried to rob us,
我引开了他们  为生意卖力
and I saved the stash. I took care of business,
就像我现在在为生意卖力一样
just like I'm taking care of business right now.
你是想站在那儿盘根问底
You want to stand there digging around,
还是换衣服干活
or you want to suit up and get to work?
你要想来的话  就换上行头
Get in gear, yo, if you want to do this
因为我下午要跟麦克出去
because I'm meeting up with Mike this afternoon.
又去  为什么
What, again? Why?
我想我想有两份工作了
Guess I have two jobs now.
洛丝・波罗斯・艾玛诺斯欢迎您
Welcome to Los Pollos Hermanos.
您要点什么
May I take your order?
受伤了吗
Any injuries?
脚踝扭了  其他没事
Twisted ankle, nothing too bad.
一切都如你所料
It all went like you thought it would,
大致如此
more or less.
当然  我会付给你
I will, of course, reimburse you
修车的钱
to the damage to your vehicle.
还有问题吗
Questions?
是有几个问题
Uh-huh. More than a few, yeah.
但我清楚还是不问为好
But I know better than to ask.
反正是如你所愿
Anyway, it was like you wanted.
那孩子立了大功
The kid's a hero.
收购洗车房的主意听起来不切实际
Just the idea of owning a car wash seems daunting,
可我必须鼓起勇气
but I had to warn myself--
谁才是世界上最美的女孩
Who is just the most beautiful little girl in the world?
我觉得那是你哦
I think it's you.
做这么一个
...so coming into a business like this
容易运营且全面运转的生意
that's up and running, fully operational,
让我们省去很多麻烦事
puts us way ahead of the game.
随着时间推移  我们仍然需要进行一些改变
You know, we're still going to have some change over time--
我们必须聘请一些员工
We have to hire some people
(对婴孩说): 我认为是你哦  没错  就是你
I think it's you. Yeah, I do.
可员工仍然是一个重要因素
But we do have a staff in place,
幸运的是  我们能留住
so, you know, luckily, we'll be able to hold on
大部分以前博格丹的员工
to most of Bogdan's employees.
我们虽然还是会被另一边的极致洗车房给挖去一些
We might lose a few to the Ultra Wash across town, though.
我听说他们正在投机取巧
They're making a grab, I hear.
你们准备让孩子也投入工作
You going to put the kid to work?
我还得去上学
I got school.
我没说你
I'm not talking about you.
我在说你的妹妹
I'm talking about your baby sister.
我才不会让你洗我的车
I wouldn't let you near my car.
那可不失为一个好主意
Hey, that's not a bad idea, you guys.
你们应该把霍莉放在醒目位置
You should put Holly on the sign.
做个吉祥物
Like a mascot?
就像招牌宝宝一样
Like the Gerber baby.
要是我看到她那美丽的脸庞
I would get my car washed there every day
我会每天都在那洗车
if I saw her face out front.
那我呢
What about me?
我们可是在招揽生意
The goal is to bring customers in,
而不是吓跑他们
not scare them away, so--
沃尔特  厨房里还有一瓶
Walt, there's another bottle in the kitchen.
自己去拿吧
Just help yourself.
好的
Ah. Good.
也许我们该让汉克叔叔去体验一番
Uh, maybe we could roll Uncle Hank through the car wash.
他就能成为我们的第一个顾客
He could be the first customer.
洗车员工会把你洗的干干净净
The wipe-down crew would clean you up good.
看见这个了么  孩子
See this, son?
我现在就给你洗洗
I got your wipe-down right here, pal.
汉克  能不能好好吃顿饭
Hank, can you just maybe get through one meal
不说那些让人恶心的东西
without you saying something disgusting?
你们准备怎么带霍莉
So what are you going to do with Holly all day?
总不能带她去工作
You can't take her to work
那里可都是化学用品和非法移民
with all those chemicals and migrants hanging around.
玛丽
Marie--
真的  那可不安全
What? That can't be safe.
幸运的是
Fortunately, there is,
离洗车房5分钟路程的地方
just five minutes away from the car wash,
有个城里顶尖的托儿所
there is the top child care center in the city.
国家托儿协会
The National Child Care Association
给它的排名很高  这事也就迎刃而解了
gives it really high ratings, so that's quite a relief,
只需离开一会就能去接她
and, you know, it's just a walk away if we need it.
我得说
I got to tell you,
我真的很感动
I'm just-- I'm really, really impressed.
我是说  你们能一起筹办这事
I mean, you came together on this,
我很高兴你们能和好如初
and I'm really happy that it's working out for you.
多谢
Thanks.
这确实有点让人提心吊胆的
It was a little scary,
但事情必须得有个结果
but it, uh, needed to be done.
我们明天就能拿到钥匙了
And, uh, we get possession of the keys tomorrow.
那太棒了
Oh, that's awesome.
是的
Yeah.
等不急想知道你们会送我什么车作为生日礼物
I can't wait to see what kind of car I'll get for my birthday,
现在我们金钱可是滚滚而来
now with all this money rolling in.
我觉得你最近一直在
I think you've been spending too much time
开汉克叔叔的玩笑
around your uncle Hank.
人善被人欺
The squeaky wheel gets the grease.
对吧  汉克叔叔
Right, Uncle Hank?
老实人可是你  老兄
Squeaky and greasy. That's you, my friend.
希腊人尼克
Hay, uh, Nick the Greek,
你还准不准被给我们喝
you going to share that bottle or what?
当然  抱歉
Oh. Yeah. Sorry.
希腊人尼克是谁
Who's Nick the Greek?
希腊人尼克  他是世界上最著名的牌手
Nick the Greek. He was a famous big-time card player.
汉克  别开那玩笑
Hank, that's not funny.
怎么  那可是在表扬他
What? It's a compliment.
我听着可不像
Well, that's even worse, then.
你得用正面思想来表达
You're giving positive reinforcement to behavior
沃尔特是通过很努力的工作才换来的结局
that Walt is working very, very hard to change.
对吧  斯凯勒
Right, Skyler?
是的
Yeah.
我没看出这有什么不好的
I don't see how it's bad, Dad,
老爸只是在短时间内大赚了一把而已
just raking in the beaucoup bucks now.
我觉得我们该换个话题了
You know, I just, uh, think maybe we could change the subject?
好的  当然
Yeah. Sure. You know.
当然啦
Absolutely.
对了汉克叔叔  你正在查的那个
Hey, Uncle Hank, what about that case you were looking at
疯狂歌手的案子怎么样了
with that crazy singing guy?
我不查了
Ah, I'm off that.
我把我的看法反馈给阿尔布开克警方  然后完事了
I-- I gave my assessment to the APD, and I'm done.
疯狂歌手的案子
The case of the crazy singing guy. Hmm.
听上去像是《百科小布朗》里的故事
Sounds like an Encyclopedia Brown story, doesn't it?
《百科小布朗》为儿童漫画侦探故事
用疯狂来形容得不太准确
Crazy is-- is-- is, uh, is the wrong word.
这人叫盖尔・伯蒂彻
This guy Gale Boetticher,
他行为古怪
he was, uh, he was eccentric.
我是说  很有个性
I mean, a real character, you know?
现在已经死了
He's, uh, he's dead now, you know.
他是谁
Huh. Who was he?
他是制造冰毒的人
He was a meth cook.
他可是个冰毒大厨
Uh, he was a meth chef.
就像五星级饭店里一样
I mean, we're talking five stars--
蜡烛加上白桌布
candles and white tablecloths.
我不敢相信我会用这词来形容他
Hey, I can't believe these words are gonna come out of my mouth,
可他确确实实是个天才
but he was a genius, plain and simple.
我是说  要是能将那样的聪明才智
I mean, uh, boy, if you applied that big brain of his
用到好的地方
to something good, I don't know,
天知道那能帮助人类
who knows what could have helped humanity
取得多少成就
or something like that, you know?
天底下能有多少个天才呢
I mean, how many actual geniuses are there in the world, right?
要是他能致力于其他的事业
If he'd kind of taken his life in a different direction,
谁知道呢
who knows?
汉克  并不是对你指手画脚
Hank, not to tell you your business,
可我并不同意你的观点
but I'm not sure I agree.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我是说  你给我看的那个笔记本
Well, I mean, you showed me that notebook and from what I saw--
就我个人观点来看
and this is just my humble opinion--
就凭那些纸上写的东西
from what I saw on those papers...
天才么
genius?
还不够格
Not so much.
我是说  那上面没有推理的过程
I mean, there was no reasoning,
没有演绎的过程
no deductions in those pages.
以我看
To my eye,
你所谓的智慧
all this brilliance looks like nothing more
只不过是简单的抄袭而已
than just simple rote copying--
也许是别人的杰作
probably of someone else's work.
相信我  我身边这样的学生多的是
Believe me, I've been around enough students to know.
你所谓的那个天才
Ah, this genius of yours...
也许还逍遥法外
maybe he's still out there.
汉克
Hank.
你好  宝贝
Hey, babe.
提姆来过
Uh, Tim stopped by.
他带来了些案子的文件
He brought over some file boxes on that case.
觉得我应该再看看
Thought I'd take another peek.
不错啊
That's great.
抱歉把家里弄乱了
Sorry about the mess.
别  别  别  不要紧
No, no, no. Don't be.
要我给你泡杯咖啡吗
You want me to make some coffee?
好的
Yeah.
那样最好不过了
Yeah, that would be good.
发现什么了吗
You find something?
只是  我在调查的这个人
Oh, just this-- this guy I'm looking at.
他所买的  所吃的东西
You know, everything he-- he-- he buys and eats
都是有机的  没有非法交易  还是个素食主义者
is organic, fair trade, vegan.
什么时候素食主义者开始吃炸鸡了
Since when the vegan eat fried chicken.